<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gitesh Wagh</title>
    <link>https://giteshwagh.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gitesh Wagh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Gitesh Wagh</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://giteshwagh.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Syntax - Complete Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/markdown-syntax-complete-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/markdown-syntax-complete-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Complete Tutorial Of Markdown Syntax Markdown is a method of writting and representing data in a beautiful way. It&#39;s widely used for creating documentation, README files, Blogs, and other types of content on the web. In this tutorial, we&#39;ll cover the basic syntax of Markdown in simple words.
1. Headings To create headings, use hash symbols (#). Use hash as per your heading level.
1# Heading 1 2 3## Heading 2 4 5### Heading 3 6 7#### Heading 4 8 9##### Heading 5 10 11###### Heading 6 Output -
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> For Loops In Python- Python Tutorials For Beginners #9</title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/for-loops-in-python-tutorial-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/for-loops-in-python-tutorial-9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Loops In Python Loops are used to execute a specific code many times instead of writing code again and again.
Types of Loops: 1. For Loops
2. While Loops
 For loop For Loop is more used than While Loops. For Loops are used for different purposes in different ways.
 In this example, I used For Loops along with the if-else statement. Here, i is List and k is a variable containing elements of list.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>💡 Introduction To Game Development </title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/introduction-to-game-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/introduction-to-game-development/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction To Game Development Introduction In the vast and ever-evolving landscape of entertainment, few mediums captivate audiences quite like video games. Game development is a harmonious blend of artistry and technology, where creative vision and technical expertise converge to create immersive digital worlds that transport players to new realms of adventure and imagination. In this blog, we&#39;ll delve into the fascinating realm of game development, exploring its key components, challenges, and the magic that turns lines of code into captivating experiences.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Hugo : World&#39;s Fastest Framework For Website Building 🔥 </title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/hugo-worlds-fastest-framework-for-website-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/hugo-worlds-fastest-framework-for-website-building/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey Guys👋, Let&#39;s Learn Everything About Hugo: The World&#39;s fastest Framework For Website Development.
What Is Hugo?  Hugo is the world&#39;s fastest framework for website building. Hugo is a fast and modern static site generator. Hugo is based on the Go programming language. It supports multiple free hosting platforms like Github, Gitlab, Netlify, etc. Hugo provides us with various templates for web designing at zero cost. Hugo is one of the popular frameworks for building a website in a few minutes.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Project 2: Calculator - Python Tutorials For Beginners #8</title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/project-2-calculator-in-python-tutorial-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/project-2-calculator-in-python-tutorial-8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Project 4 : Calculator In Python This Python project is a basic calculator that performs arithmetic operations on two numbers. The project employs fundamental programming concepts like functions, if-else statements, variables, and datatypes to provide a simple calculator interface.
Here&#39;s a description of the project in simple language:
  Introduction and Instructions: The program begins by displaying a message to the user. It explains how to use the calculator by entering specific keywords like &#39;add&#39;, &#39;sub&#39;, &#39;multi&#39;, &#39;div&#39;, and &#39;power&#39; for different arithmetic operations.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Match Cases - Python Tutorials For Beginners #7</title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/match-cases-in-python-tutorial-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/match-cases-in-python-tutorial-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            WHAT ARE MATCH CASES IN PYTHON? Match Cases is a method for writing conditions in Python programming. Here, We create conditions related to the value of a variable. In If-Else statements, we define the condition with the help of conditional operators. But, Here, In Match Cases the value of the variable is a condition. In Match Cases we write, What will happen when the value of a variable is 1, 2, 3, etc.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> If-Else statements - Python Tutorials For Beginners #6</title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/if-else-statements-in-python-tutorial-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/if-else-statements-in-python-tutorial-6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What is If-Else statement ? An if-Else statement is a method for writing conditions. Another method available today is match cases. We start writing our first condition by using the &#39;if&#39; keyword and the other by using the keyword &#39;elif&#39;. The last condition was else it runs when other conditions will not execute. Every condition contains some code, It runs when the condition will be executed.
Writing technique:-
Steps for writing condition:-
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operators In Python - Python Tutorials For Beginners #5</title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/operators-in-python-tutorial-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/operators-in-python-tutorial-5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What Are Operators In Python? Operators are a symbol or small word which is useful to perform operations in Python.  Type Of Operators (1) Conditional Operators (2) Logical Operators (3) Identity Operators (4) Arithmetic Operators (5) Membership Operators (6) Assignment Operators (7) Bitwise Operator  Conditional / Comparison Operators In Python 1Conditional / Comparison Operators In Python 2 3&amp;lt; Greater Than symbol 4&amp;gt; Smaller Than symbol 5&amp;lt;= Equal To And Greater Than 6&amp;gt;= Equal To And Smaller Than 7== Equal To 8!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Coin Toss - Python Tutorials For Beginners #4</title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/coin-toss-project-python-tutorial-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/coin-toss-project-python-tutorial-4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let’s Create Something Amazing With Python!
In this blog, we’ll be learning how to create a Python program to make a simple coin toss project. This project is perfect for beginners. Today, We all learn about the practical application of concepts in Python.
This program will allow the computer to randomly choose one of two outcomes and display it.
Concepts Used In This Project (1) Variables
(2) Datatypes
(3) Random Module
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variables And DataTypes - Python Tutorials For Beginners #3</title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/variables-and-datatypes-python-tutorial-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/variables-and-datatypes-python-tutorial-3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Variables 1Variabl1e1 = 24565876575678 2x = input() 3print(x) 4print(Variabl1e1) Here I created a variable called &amp;quot;Variable1&amp;quot;. Variables are use for storing data. Variables are like containers, they contain values.** First of all, write the name of the variable, Use the = sign, and assign the value. This is the syntax to create variables in Python programming.
These are some example variables.
1a = 12345 2b = &amp;#34;abc123&amp;#34; 3c = 12.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Basics Of Python - Python Tutorials For Beginners #2</title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/basics-of-python-tutorial-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/basics-of-python-tutorial-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            1.print() 1print(&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;Hello World 2I am the coder 3this is my first progrm.&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;) Print is a function that is used to display value. Print is an essential function in Python programming. Print is a simple but very useful function. We generally use a Print function to display string and integer values. Print is the first function that we learn during Python programming. Print function are display the string, integer and float values.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Installation and Setup of Python and VS Codium - Python Tutorials For Beginners #1 </title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/setup-of-python-tutorial-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/setup-of-python-tutorial-1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello Friends👋, You know that Python is the most straightforward programming language for beginners. Today, We will see how to download and set up Python with VS Codium. VS Codium is an Integrated Development Environment (IDE). VS Codium is a simple and powerful tool for coding.
VS Codium provides many important and latest features. VS Codium is a lightweight but powerful tool. VS Codium helps you a lot in your coding journey.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Our First Program In C#| C# Tutorials #2 </title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/creating-our-first-program-c-sharp-tutorial-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/creating-our-first-program-c-sharp-tutorial-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Before creating our first program we will create a project.
Step 1: Open Visual Studio.
Step 2: Click on &amp;quot;Create New Project&amp;quot;
Step 3: Select Language C#. Choose a platform(Our OS).
Step 4: The project type will be &#39;console&#39;
Our first program is printing of &amp;quot;HelloWorld&amp;quot;
Code:-
1 2using System; 3using System.Collections.Generic; 4using System.Linq; 5using System.Text; 6using System.Threading.Tasks; 7 8 9 10namespace ConsoleApp1 // The namespace is like a container it stores Classes and methods// 11 12{ 13 class Program 14 15 { 16 static void Main(string[] args) 17 18 { 19 Console.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction To C# Programming Language - C# Tutorials For Beginners #1</title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/introduction-to-c-sharp-tutorial-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/introduction-to-c-sharp-tutorial-1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C#(C sharp) is a programming language developed by Microsoft. C# runs on .NET Framework.
C# is used to develop the following applications and software :
 Mobile Apps Video Games Desktop Apps Web Apps Graphical User Interface(GUI)  Microsoft Visual Studio is one of the best Integrated Development Environment (IDE) and Code Editor for C#.
Step 1: Download Visual Studio Installer Now, We will start to download Visual Studio to start programming.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Kdenlive Is The Best Free Video Editor?</title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/why-kdenlive-is-the-best-free-video-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/why-kdenlive-is-the-best-free-video-editor/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kdenlive is a free video editor. Today, Video editing is an important skill for content creators. The video editor is essential tool for video editing after editing skills. Kdenlive is free and open-source software for video editing. Kdenlive is lightweight and runs on 4GB ram only.
Specification for Kdenlive: 1.Operating System = Windows 7 or newer
 Processor = 2 cores for SD video, 4 cores for HD video, and 8 cores for 4K video.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Coding Will Become The Most Valuable Skill In The Future?</title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/why-coding-will-become-the-most-valuable-skill-in-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/why-coding-will-become-the-most-valuable-skill-in-the-future/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What Is Coding? Basically, Coding way to interact and assigning task to a computer.
What Is Programming languages? The language which computer understands are called Programming Languages.
Example - Python, C, C++, Ruby, etc...
Hey guys,
You know 2023 is coming and you also know the technology is growing very fast in 2019, 2020, and 2021 and it is also growing in the COVID-19 pandemic. In the tech field, we have various options to enter and a large amount of scope with a good salary for our skills.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://giteshwagh.com/post/type-casting-in-python-tutorial-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giteshwagh.com/post/type-casting-in-python-tutorial-10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            title = &amp;quot;Type Casting In Python- Python Tutorials For Beginners #10&amp;quot; date = &amp;quot;2023-10-11&amp;quot; categories = &amp;quot;Python&amp;quot; tags = [ &amp;quot;Programming&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Coding&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;python&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PythonTutorial&amp;quot; ] thumbnail = &amp;quot;/images/PythonTutorial10.png&amp;quot; +++
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
